# ROHAN MAHARJAN

Yengal, Kathmandu, Nepal · 9841171088 maharoh9841@gmail.com

Goal-oriented Web Developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem- solving. Use various web design software to develop customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of end-users. Successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective customer support.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **JULY 2020 - PRESENT**

### **ANGULAR DEVELOPER, NEPASOFT PVT. LTD**

- Research and Development on Syncfusion PDF viewer and its features such as annotation.
- Research and Development on loading PDF in PDFTron viewer along with adding annotations.

## AUGUST 2018 – FEBRUARY 2020 WEB DEVELOPER, IT NEPAL PVT. LTD.

- Tested programs and databases to identify issues and make necessary modifications.
- Build, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment
- Developed object-oriented software, including CRM for use in various companies
- Collaborated with developers to enhance supportability and identify performance bottlenecks.
- Coordinated with project management staff on database development timeliness and project scope
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.

#### OCTOBER 2017 - JANUARY 2018

# SECURITY OPERATION CENTER ASSISTANT, EUROPEAN UNION ELECTION OBSERVATION MISSION

• Various IT related duties and responsibilities such as office packages, designing in Photoshop.

- Maintaining a daily day/night watch and monitoring of vehicle movements (vehicle satellite tracking system).
- Maintain daily tracking reports
- Recording and reporting of any event affecting the security of the mission.
- Archive working documents.
- Providing useful support to any type of urgent request.

#### **MARCH 2016 – APRIL 2017**

## JUNIOR PROGRAMMER, ARHANT SOLUTIONS

- Wrote highly maintainable code in .NET framework for various systems that formed core framework
- Monitored and updated backend data by intercommunicating between .NET Framework and SQL Server
- Debugged and modified various projects software components.
- Designed and developed computer software web applications.
- Analyzed and designed relational databases using SQL Server.

## **EDUCATION**

**JANUARY 2018** 

# MASTER OF ARTS MASS COMMUNICATION AND JOURNALISM, KANTIPUR CITY COLLEGE

Running, Purbanchal University

**AUGUST 2017** 

### **BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATION, COLLEGE OF INFORMATION**

TECHNOLOGY AND ENGINEERING

CGPA 3.04, Purbanchal University

OCTOBER 2012

**INTERMEDIATE, NATIONAL COLLEGE OF COMPUTER STUDIES** 

Percentage 67.00%, HSEB

**MARCH 2010** 

SCHOOL LEAVING CERTIFICATE, ARNIKO BOARDING SCHOOL

Percentage 77.63%, Nepal Government

## **SKILLS**

- Angular 5+
- SQL Server

- NET MVC Framework
- .NET Core 2.1+
- HTML/CSS/JS

## **ACTIVITIES**

- Volunteered for CAN Info Tech (September 2013)
- Trained for Graphics Design and Computer Hardware from Computer Planet